# **BENJAMIN KRUG**

821 Deer Clover Cir. Castle Pines, CO 80108

(970) 744-9172 <u>Benjamin.David.Krug@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>https://github.com/bekr1024</u>

#### **SKILLS**

Strong mathematical and physical reasoning, with experience in computer programming and scripting. Proficient with C++ and Python, and experienced in web languages such as CSS and HTML. Interests include machine learning, encryption algorithms, and remote automation techniques.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Quality Inspector | Accu-Precision, Inc

- Inspected and approved parts machined to the highest standards possible, in order to satisfy the requirements of aerospace, military, and other tight-tolerance contractors.
- Approved machined parts using optical comparators, height gages, CMMs, and other precisioncalibrated devices for fast and reliable data acquisition.
- Quickly mastered measurement and documentation procedures to ensure customers received the highest quality products in the shortest timeframe, with documentation always organized to customer satisfaction.
- Performed inspections based on ISO 9000, AS 9100, and other high precision standards.

# Quality Production Operator | Vestas Blades Americas, Inc

2015 - 2017

- Responsibilities included the quality inspection and production of 54m turbine blades.
- Took responsibility for every stage of the build, infusion, and gluing processes, focusing on defect prevention and effective use of repairs.
- Documented build dimensions and detailed all repairs performed on each blade, evaluating with custom gages as well as industry-standard equipment such as calipers, thermal imaging cameras, and go/no-go gages.
- Trained and supported production and quality team members to build a more quality-oriented production culture.

## **Programmer | CNE Creative Enterprises**

2015 - 2016

- Responsibilities included software programming for embedded control systems using BASH, Python, and C++. Developed software for Arduino, Raspberry Pi, and other custom hardware platforms.
- Developed, tested, and refined custom software for the testing of automated vending machine systems to specifications given by the customer.
- Implemented and simplified algorithms for interfacing with measurement devices and controlling the actions of the vending machine accordingly.
- Used HTML, CSS, MySQL while designing and managing various websites both in-house and for other clients
- Evaluated existing database information and developed new scripting to troubleshoot and solve existing database errors.
- Routinely worked directly with hardware systems using oscilloscopes, digital volt meters, and other standard electronic equipment.

# Laboratory Research Assistant | University of Colorado

2014 - 2015

- Studied the optical and mechanical effects of temperature change on photo-polymerized liquid crystal particles using high powered UV lasers.
- Used glass cleaning and preparation techniques to optimize the alignment of nematic colloidal liquid crystal material for microscopic observations under polarized light filters.
- Explored different material, optical, and thermal procedures to troubleshoot material failures of liquid crystal samples, using custom heating plates and varying heating and cooling techniques to eliminate potential preparation errors.

## Aerial Fireworks Pyrotechnician | Firestorm Pyrotechnics, Inc.

2010 - Present

- Fireworks display operator in charge of the setup, loading, fusing, wiring, and execution of professional fireworks displays.
- Coordinated the handling of heavy equipment and flammable products onto and off of the display field.
- Developed processes to the setup and fusing of devices, providing feedback to other pyrotechnicians on fusing and setup techniques.
- Reduced performance failures by 90% during first year of coordinating processes on field.
- Provided ballistics calculations for a team of pyrotechnicians to earn the Guinness World Record for the largest firework ever created.

## **EDUCATION**